<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Alexey Artemov</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Alexey Artemov</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Yuanyuan GE 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://artonson.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AutoInst: Automatic Instance-Based Segmentation of LiDAR 3D Scans</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2024-autoinst/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2024-autoinst/</guid><description>Visual Results on KITTI 3DUIS HDBSCAN OURS (NCut) Ours (NCut + Refined)</description></item><item><title>DeepMIF: Deep Monotonic Implicit Fields for Large-Scale LiDAR 3D Mapping</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2024-deepmif/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2024-deepmif/</guid><description>Sample Reconstruction Results We have tested our approach vs. NeRF-LOAM, Make it Dense, SHINE-Mapping, PUMA, and VDBFusion.
Mai City Mai City is a simulated environment commonly used for benchmarking scene reconstruction algorithms.
Shaded render Precision map Newer College Newer College is a building belonging to Oxford University. It was scanned using a hand-held LiDAR (common input data for reconstruction) and a terrestrial industrial LiDAR (common reference data for evaluation).
Shaded render Precision map KITTI KITTI is the best known, and the most commonly used benchmark for autonomous driving algorithms.</description></item><item><title>PRS: Sharp Feature Priors for Resolution-Free Surface Remeshing</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2024-prs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2024-prs/</guid><description/></item><item><title>MeshGPT: Generating Triangle Meshes with Decoder-Only Transformers</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2024-meshgpt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2024-meshgpt/</guid><description/></item><item><title>SSR-2D: Semantic 3D Scene Reconstruction from 2D Images</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2024-ssr-2d/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2024-ssr-2d/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Conservation of Cultural Heritage Artifacts for State Historical Museum</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/art/2021-shm-pilot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/art/2021-shm-pilot/</guid><description>Task State Historical Museum seeks to develop a sustainable methodology for digitizing its collection of unique historical artefacts and surveying its buildings. This pilot project includes creating of digital replicas of two unique objects from SHM collection and 3D models of separate spaces in the Pokrovsky Cathedral.
3D Scanning and Image Capture Process We have found that using only photo camera or only a 3D scanner does not lead to satisfactory results and decided to combine accurate 3D geometry captured by the laser scanner and high-quality, high-resolution images acquired by a DSLR camera.</description></item><item><title>Skoltech3D: Multi-sensor large-scale dataset for multi-view 3D reconstruction</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2023-sk3d/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2023-sk3d/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Foundations of Software Engineering</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/teaching/fse/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/teaching/fse/</guid><description>Course Contents Topics include:
Unix fundamentals: shell and command line, scripting, filesystem, streams and pipes, parameter parsing, remote machine, and ssh, etc., Software engineering in teams: code review and version control, reproducibility and containers, testing and test-driven development, improving code style, software deployment, and APIs, etc., Software design: team organization, software specifications, software project management, software design methodologies, object-oriented software design, etc. As a project, the students will be required to work in teams to design, engineer, test, and deploy a real large software system using the principles described in this course.</description></item><item><title>Towards Unpaired Depth Enhancement and Super-Resolution in the Wild</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2021-unpaired-depth-sr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2021-unpaired-depth-sr/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:46:57 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/about/</guid><description>This is the source code for the about page.</description></item><item><title>Geometric Computer Vision</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/teaching/gcv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/teaching/gcv/</guid><description>Course Contents Lecture 1. Course introduction and overview. The geometry processing pipeline. 3D representations in vision and graphics Lecture 2. Hardware systems for 3D data acquisition Lecture 3. Dense [2D] range images Lecture 4. Point set-based modalities. Invariance and equivariance in learning. Lecture 5. Learning from volumetric depth Lecture 6. Learning with implicit functions Lecture 7. Surface modalities Lecture 8. CAD/vectorized modalities</description></item><item><title>Towards Part-Based Understanding of RGB-D Scans</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2021-towards-part-based/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2021-towards-part-based/</guid><description/></item><item><title>DEF: Deep Estimation of Sharp Geometric Features in 3D Shapes</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2022-def/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2022-def/</guid><description/></item><item><title>CAD-Deform: Deformable Fitting of CAD Models to 3D Scans</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2020-cad-deform/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2020-cad-deform/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Making DensePose Fast and Light</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2021-dense-pose/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2021-dense-pose/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Latent Video Transformer</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2021-lvt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2021-lvt/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Deep Vectorization of Technical Drawings</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2020-deep-vectorization/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2020-deep-vectorization/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Machine Learning in High Energy Physics&lt;br/> Summer Schools (2017—2019)</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/teaching/mlhep/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/teaching/mlhep/</guid><description>There are plenty of essential problems in high energy physics that can be solved using Machine Learning methods. These vary from online data filtering and reconstruction to offline data analysis.
Students of the school will receive a theoretical and practical introduction to this new field and will be able to apply acquired knowledge to solve their own problems. Topics ranging from decision trees to deep learning and hyperparameter optimisation will be covered with concrete examples and hands-on tutorials.</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning Summer School 2019</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/teaching/mlss/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/teaching/mlss/</guid><description>Specific days where I participated were:
DAY-2 (27.08): Alexey Artemov, Justin Solomon - Geometric Techniques in ML DAY-8 (04.09): Alexey Artemov, Michael Bronstein - Graph Neural Networks</description></item><item><title>Monocular 3D Object Detection via Geometric Reasoning on Keypoints</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2019-monocular-3d/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2019-monocular-3d/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Perceptual Deep Depth Super-Resolution</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2019-perceptual-deep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2019-perceptual-deep/</guid><description/></item><item><title>ABC: A Big CAD Model Dataset for Geometric Deep Learning</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2019-abc-dataset/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/publications/2019-abc-dataset/</guid><description/></item><item><title>AI Jewelry Design for Oktaaf</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/art/2021-oktaaf-cufflinks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/art/2021-oktaaf-cufflinks/</guid><description>Oktaaf Oktaaf is the brainchild of Spanish jewelry designer Ainoa Corres and Belgian internet entrepreneur Karel De Beule. Ainoa and Karel carefully select small historical artefacts, to integrate them into wearable, contemporary jewelry.
AI Cufflinks One of the most astonishing objects in the entire collection of jewelry pieces designed by Oktaaf is undoubtedly a pair of cufflinks created with the help of artificial intelligence. Natalia and Alexey helped them come up with an shape for this breakthrough idea.</description></item><item><title>Applied Statistics in Machine Learning</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/teaching/asml/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/teaching/asml/</guid><description>Course Contents Lecture 1. Course introduction. Lecture 2. Resampling. Monte Carlo simulation. Bootstrap. Confidence intervals. Multiple comparisons correction. Bagging in machine learning. Lecture 3. Parametric estimation. Maximum likelihood method and its properties. Delta method. The case of vector parameter. Lecture 4. Distances between distributions. f-divergence distances. The distance of total variation. Kulbak-Leibler distance. Jensen-Shannon distance. χ2 distance. Wasserstein distance. Lecture 5. Hypothesis testing (Part 1). Statistical hypotheses and statistical criteria. Characteristics of the criteria.</description></item><item><title>Coursera AML: Deep Learning in Computer Vision</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/teaching/coursera_aml/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/teaching/coursera_aml/</guid><description>Course Contents Deep learning added a huge boost to the already rapidly developing field of computer vision. With deep learning, a lot of new applications of computer vision techniques have been introduced and are now becoming parts of our everyday lives. These include face recognition and indexing, photo stylization or machine vision in self-driving cars.
The goal of this online course is to introduce students to computer vision, starting from basics and then turning to more modern deep learning models.</description></item><item><title>Statistics of Random Processes</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/teaching/smsrp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/teaching/smsrp/</guid><description>Course Contents Lecture 1. Stochastic processes and their characteristics. Lecture 2. Theory fundamentals of stochastic processes. Lecture 3. Wiener and Poisson type processes. Generation of realizations of random processes. Lecture 4. Markov chains. Lecture 5. Markov processes. Lecture 6. Stochastic models with discrete time. Lecture 7. Gaussian and conditional Gaussian models. Lecture 8. Hidden Markov models. Lecture 9. Multivariate Gaussian estimation. Kalman filter. Lecture 10. Key statistics and tests in decision theory.</description></item></channel></rss>