<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Arts on Alexey Artemov</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/art/</link><description>Recent content in Arts on Alexey Artemov</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Yuanyuan GE 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://artonson.github.io/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Conservation of Cultural Heritage Artifacts for State Historical Museum</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/art/2021-shm-pilot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/art/2021-shm-pilot/</guid><description>Task State Historical Museum seeks to develop a sustainable methodology for digitizing its collection of unique historical artefacts and surveying its buildings. This pilot project includes creating of digital replicas of two unique objects from SHM collection and 3D models of separate spaces in the Pokrovsky Cathedral.
3D Scanning and Image Capture Process We have found that using only photo camera or only a 3D scanner does not lead to satisfactory results and decided to combine accurate 3D geometry captured by the laser scanner and high-quality, high-resolution images acquired by a DSLR camera.</description></item><item><title>AI Jewelry Design for Oktaaf</title><link>https://artonson.github.io/art/2021-oktaaf-cufflinks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://artonson.github.io/art/2021-oktaaf-cufflinks/</guid><description>Oktaaf Oktaaf is the brainchild of Spanish jewelry designer Ainoa Corres and Belgian internet entrepreneur Karel De Beule. Ainoa and Karel carefully select small historical artefacts, to integrate them into wearable, contemporary jewelry.
AI Cufflinks One of the most astonishing objects in the entire collection of jewelry pieces designed by Oktaaf is undoubtedly a pair of cufflinks created with the help of artificial intelligence. Natalia and Alexey helped them come up with an shape for this breakthrough idea.</description></item></channel></rss>